the following is a production of Frankie
Freitas and the internet will exam of
holography
[Music]
hello everyone this is Frankie Freitas
and welcome to another week of Holo talk
for the week of September 27 1999. this
week Our Guest is Sam goldwasser this is
the part two conclusion of the interview
that began last week and this week Sam
talks about green DPSS lasers he gives
tips for buying used lasers on the web
such as from eBay talked a little bit
about his home laser lab and also makes
comments on diode coherence and
different laser links on the world wide
web so this segment runs around 40
minutes we're going to get right into it
but first I just want to give you a
reminder about October 6 which is the
first open house here at the studio
where you can come in hear a little bit
about holography see some Holograms and
I believe the Topic's going to be laser
transmission Holograms so if you've
never had a chance to see laser
transmission Holograms come out through
the studio the night of October 6 1999
which is coming up and should be a nice
evening it starts at 7 30 and in fact we
have a little short segment here that
Debbie Lee put together so we're going
to get into that
information about it contact me let me
know if you'd like to comment below I've
already got a few people signed up so we
hope to see you here too so here we go
here's the interview with Sam Goldwater
right after this message
[Music]
would you like to create your own
three-dimensional Holograms well you can
begin today and Frankie Freitas can show
you how from introductory guides like a
shoebox philosophy system to developing
Innovative and affordable new laser
systems along with year-round
photography Workshop programs Frank is
finding the way to bring the attic reach
into the reach of everyone from
September through May you can attend one
of his free evening lecture series at
the studio in Allentown Pennsylvania
which is a quick non-stop drive from the
New York Philadelphia Baltimore and
Washington DC areas offered the first
Wednesday of every month Frank Begins
the evening at 7 30 with the talking
holography followed by a tour of the lab
and a chance to be Holograms in his
personal collection there is no cost to
attend the Wednesday evening lecture
that you must call in advance or send an
email to make reservations to reach the
studio for more information or can make
reservations for the Wednesday evening
lecture series please call toll-free
1-800-458-3525 or send an email from the
website that number again is
1-800-458-3525 to attend a Wednesday
evening lecture at the studio Frank
hopes to see you there
[Music]
was a nice uh entry to your site when
the green laser pointer write this on
the photos
to spend 300 on a pointer and then take
it apart yeah I couldn't see that but
good thanks for being thankful for
people who are willing to experiment
like that I did that with my first
module and I paid 300 and some dollars
for it was a 10 milliwatt and it was
sitting here it was just driving me
crazy you know I said I've got to get
this apart but I'll tell you something
they put that epoxy in there how do you
know he's listening to this show do not
you're just going to waste your time
trying to practice things apart
just about cried fortunately this laser
pointer is the I'm not sure exactly what
was holding it together
yeah and then it was working
individually
and then I added some other pictures I
don't know what happened but he
block of aluminum that he
couldn't do but I
powered up I don't know what happened
after that but that's that's an amazing
sequence of pictures yeah I'd love to
get one of those on the table I have a
whole box of panchromatic holographic
plates here that's
to uh red green and green right and I'd
love to uh I don't know how good the
quality yeah see I don't know and some
of them are pulse too right right
what's a DPSS stand for diode pump solid
state okay but that's all these lasers
where you have a massive
lab
and then
you get the 10th 10064 nanometers out
directly or then you double it you know
I kind of call DPSS FD for frequency
doubles those doubling crystals are
pretty expensive
and what's the deal with that do you
think you're really supposed to be that
expensive I think it's the volume right
now they're making they're making those
crystals in literally meter
National
Authority that big laser that that
unofficially is to study how how a
nuclear bomb
both both the studies and plasma
but then try to do research on inertia
combining confusion power we all know
that the real reason they're building
that Blazers lasers scientists like to
play with big lasers
but uh
these slots there are literally
the final amplifier that has
a couple something like 184 B lines
you have each one the final amplifier
order of a half a meter across it would
be made of these slabs of doubling the
frequency doubling crystals they can
make the stuff in big matches they
recently
they do it I think it might find it in a
Russian
that they throw these crystals literally
uh
hundreds of pounds
[Laughter]
laser or one of the other Livermore
lasers and they look really intriguing I
mean you get if you can get yourself a
sweet a big fan
Big Flash but he's selling two and three
foot long rods
that's incredible I don't know if
they're good for anything but
I probably got for a buck a pound or
something I don't know
well you know you just reminded me of
something well I'll have you on here you
might be able to give a few tips to
people who might be tuning in and are
looking to get a laser and they go onto
eBay now we know we see a lot of posts
on all lasers when someone posts on eBay
you know 10 10 milliwatt helium neon
laser with power supply for six dollars
wow what's the story with some of that
stuff all right send your warnings out
first of all the first warning about
laser posing with eBay is that and I
would say probably 75 of the cases the
seller posts the
cdr8 safety sticker rating of the laser
not the actual power yeah this mostly
applies to helium neon and argon lasers
the other ones probably not so much but
he for example something rated 10
milliwatt helium neon laser may actually
only put out less than five milliwatts
the five milliwatt rated laser may put
out
he wanted to typically and there is no
way with the healing mayonnaise to boost
power yeah what what you get is what you
get so if you see something for a 30 ml
watt laser and the laser tubes four
inches long
yeah 30 milliwatt laser right again it's
four inches long I don't think so
it must be a very special kind of place
uh the uh that's the first thing the
second thing of course is that the Deep
prices on eBay go way higher than
stuff's worth very often it it has very
variable the same laser on the given day
may be they sell off for twenty dollars
or 150
you you're much better off checking
around first of all do your research
check around the laser Surplus places
and find out what they're selling lasers
for now when you send a laser I I have
them here you know the cylindrical vents
with the power supplies yeah there's no
shutter there's no indicator light
there's no uh delay at the lake
circuitry unless there is one in the
brick power supply
all these things aren't they required by
the cdrh happen they sell that to the
public without it it's not clear what's
going on yeah I don't know if
pdrh volume
now the very small volumes going on here
but in my opinion it is violating some
some regulations
some of them have the shutters
you can always disabled delay by cutting
that wire on the brick
and uh
nothing I I don't want to say that that
I don't think regulations here
it's a low volume
there really should be some way that
people
who buy these things are you know you
can make sure they're qualified not to
not to stick the thing in their eye or
something
I mean people buy these things don't
don't understand the difference between
a 20
20 laser and a laser pointer
and why would a 15 mL or tube in power
supply
my daughter answered the door and signed
for it UPS right and this was this was a
while ago right and then a little while
ago I had bought a laser pointer when we
were doing all these little experiments
and stuff UPS driver brings it and says
that she can't sign for it because it's
a laser pointer but
before that she signed for 15 million
with the power supply you know but
declared to the laser I don't know yeah
that's a good point probably other than
half the time you think they're just I
know whenever I buy this stuff well
either off eBay or from somebody private
I mean there's no declaration there's no
refusing the UPS or or uh
priority mail something like that uh we
did this thing when I had that
I bought an argon power supply from some
guy in Canada and uh
they were worried the guy was worried
that there'd be a custom problems
um
there's nothing else about
eBay I think we were talking mostly
about not to get suckered into believing
the power that's it the first first
thing is there's a there's a certain
amount of information in the laser fact
about some common model lasers and the
power there's also a site on the net
search engine that will search its
database for common helium neon laser
and argon laser model numbers
the one that you're interested but that
can then tell you the rated power yeah
now a laser may put out more than a
traded power when it's new yes
twice the traded power when it's new but
there's really no way on an eBay post
you're gonna know how much use it's at
how often yeah and I think yeah the main
thing to think to keep in mind there is
that
know what the value what you place the
value to be what what you think the
value of what you're bidding on the
billion then stick to your pipe is
because there always be others
teenagers they're going to be more and
more coming on the market because
they're going to be replaced with with
diodes and DPSS type places they're just
going to be flooding the market
prices will come
I've looked
at an easy day I can't track them daily
I tracked eBay lasers I have a bunch of
that will get you most of the laser
equipment on eBay I'm going to put a 5
million watt heanie up there for seven
hours oh there was there's one I had one
million one yeah
you gotta love this field and it's going
to get even more interesting as time
goes on oh sure yeah sure I've noticed
that with the you know since the laser
pointers came in came in now it's a
completely new complexion to the whole
field you know that's that's something I
did want to bring out about the kind of
media hype about the hazards the laser
pointer yeah yeah uh
true that theoretically it's possible
you could hurt yourself with a laser
pointer you worked at it but you're not
going to do it across the stadium you're
talking
to the eye you know for a fraction of
effect yeah I mean you have to stare at
that thing for seconds or minutes to get
any have any chance permit that then and
some of those type
see the headlines that people down
in the permanent division damage to
spectator that uh
no I don't think so
now that's
that's contrast with laser shows where
they're using high power
foreign
they have to have a margin they're not
well regulated yeah after the margin to
assure they don't exceed that five mil a
lot
more importantly from their point of
view that they don't blow the diode
so they're probably more like two or
three why why is it that you can get a
uh no I'm assuming that they have like a
five milliwatt diode in these that are
sickness 96 50 nanometer Grinders yeah
why is it you can buy a pointer with a
650 nanometer diode in there five
milliwatt diode and get that pointer for
maybe seven or ten dollars but you go
into a regular laser diode supplier
website or whatever and you look up a
650 nanometer five milliwatt raw diode
or even the module and you're looking
like 139 dollars for it for the module
yeah
the module doesn't have anything more
than the laser pointer it's got the
driver circuitry it's got the
collimating lens and it's got the actual
diode my feeling I don't know for sure
my feeling is that largely largely a
matter of the volume
you get Supply in the map yeah I think
that I I there has been speculation that
the diode sold to laser pointer
manufacturers are built
but I
thought oh I saw it today
670 nanometers like who gives a crap
about that anymore right five milliwatt
output for
369 dollars
no actually it wasn't but I know what
you're talking about yeah can you
believe that well yeah I I don't I I
guess I can believe it I don't know if
there's anything special about that
thought I'd have to send you the link to
that you have to remember you know what
Link's got
me oh in fact I know where that is I'll
send that to you in an email and you got
to go check that out and I think they
have another one that's like 650
nanometers or no it's 635
five milliwatt and it's 600 and some
dollars I I was given a 635
module actually ripped it out of pizza
equipment was being thrown out two or
three years ago you had a 635 in it yeah
it was it was actually a
company's prototype for a
system this is a system that's used to
kind of Mark on a patient and put a b
put a line on the patient where where
their uh decision but
foreign
this is another buyer beware oh okay
um I'm not sure how pervasive it is but
I've seen some cases more than one where
when you buy a laser point
s or did it's actually six seven six
fifty eight
interesting
yeah 658 is what we're working with with
the 35mm it's a beautiful red bean I
love that it's so rich it's so rich at 6
58. yeah when I go to the supermarket I
look at they look at the scanner and say
oh that's a 670
right now I'm I'm continuing to plot
along and that stuff I mean it gets
updated to alien facts you know I don't
know I'm not always digital about
changing version numbers but the laser
fact
as I find out little things here and
there I I add information to get in
so it continues to grow I don't know how
long it's going to continue
realistically it is kind of just kind of
secret that
I usually retain an interest in
something for about six years oh I see
we're laser factor in the current form
is less than two years old I think
you're safe yeah
I mean actually yet
evolved from that 18 kilobyte article to
what it is today and in fact I just
after you emailed me about being on the
show I I went and did a uh a word count
on on it
it's literally 600 000 words just text
right now I mean that doesn't include
all the millions of bytes of data in the
pictures and diagrams but just the app
is the 600 000 words or 3.8 million
characters
that's all those in ends in there and
mw's that's right I think that I did
that on if I did a search for those that
probably comes out
uh it was great having you on the show
finally and we are pretty close I guess
to being neighbors right I mean I was
surprised
I'm from Philly well you just just at
the turnpike yeah exit 33. I mean I can
I can be down in Philly in I don't know
30 or 40 minutes
I'd probably be disappointed I mean
that's not like I have this great The
Fabulous laugh and everything what's the
way I feel about this I'm always
apologizing for it you know and it's
always a mess I try to clean it up but
it only lasts from about two or three
days before it's back to the way it was
I always apologize when people come in
some of them when they look at it they
feel like they may not get out alive
well if you came over now you'd find
that I kind of I used to have a dark
room
silver photography is kind of well for
photography I mean who does it anymore
yeah I mean It's All Digital I mean I I
I I fully simplify and understand people
with their their high quality cameras
and I have my
time
for 35 millimeter cameras but I never
get to use them anymore I mean for quick
quality photography you still can't do
that but realistically
I didn't
offering work in the 15 or 20 years so I
cleaned that out just got including
we've got laser stuff and other stuff in
it but
he came over right now you'd find a it
you'd find a teeny tube with external
mirrors I'm trying to get working some
of them yeah
but I built the resonator frame for
Mirror maps and stuff I I'm trying to
get
a 30 inch long you need to but that's a
strange one that kind of works but I
can't get as much power out of it as I'd
like I did find a really strange tube
that has had a central portion of its
output popular mirror Blown Away wow
it's gone nobody can figure out what
happened I mean someone when in the
inside took a little bit of the steel
wool and just break off and start the
decoding on the mirror so it goes right
there's no beam obviously
nobody can figure out what happened
they're being sitting ordinary little
tube but the kind of came out of the
post office
guy well maybe you uh you were aligning
your high power Ruby laser I forgot to
remove it you do the alignment laser
when you fired it up
idea what happened maybe uh
one of the aliens from that guy's
pyramid webpage
they're all they're kind of intriguing
possibilities what can you do with the
tube that had the Clear Window at one
end yeah
I mean it must be something you should
do with that surprometry or some kind of
thing to do with that but no Outlet
being there right no output being but
then question is reflectivity of what's
left there too high
American yeah I don't know I think
but something I might try something
they seem like you've always got
something going on there well yeah I
always have something going on and uh I
don't know it keeps me out of trouble at
least yes and I look at it and you know
there's something rewarding about
knowing that you have I have the uh the
only fight in the world it's extent for
the amount of information yeah it's
incredible it really is there I don't
think there's any sites like that here
not just for lasers but I mean if you're
a listener pick a topic I don't know
automotive repair or uh well they can
repair stuff is also unique I mean the
consumers there that's that's
over here there are people I'm sure that
there's certain areas I haven't dealt
with like computer repair I figure there
are plenty of people that can do that
have have the major amount of
information on that but the consumer
electronics you might find a site where
any single one of those things they do
well but nobody doesn't laugh at least
a little bit of that each night
sit back with like a cup of coffee or
something and just get started
when I think of it I think it's
something to add or I can get posting on
a news group but say hey well maybe that
should be in the should be added the
laser back or the repair
or uh I mean it used to be that I
actually would sit down and write this
stuff but now
the repair facts are pretty much in
their final form they're not going to
get a lot bigger they're they're pretty
much there
I
it's just uh only there's only so much I
can do
that's not enough information for people
around they're hopelessly you can feel
the death of the gas laser coming
against you
it's been coming for
me it's
still however you know if if you can
come up with a repeatable inexpensive
way of producing the same quality demons
as The Gaslight that produces from a
diet then it's
gone
I I suspect right now it's still not
quite at that point even though you know
you you have an example of it and this
guy was a venture barometer has an
example of it there's no doubt and
there's other examples of that
maybe laser companies don't sell them
anymore and I think it's still
like physics
I mean they're not emphasizing them but
they but they still have it's still
important
what are they manufacturing for anymore
that the solid-state diode laser hasn't
taken over I know they used to be in the
supermarket scanners
many years ago I had a laser disc player
that had a hand
foreign
cavity yeah generally the rule of thumb
is about the length of the lazy cavity
because
they had to move along the way you have
to move out of phase by a half a
wavelength before and you're out of
coherence type and headlight the laser
cavity is a good
I mean everyone had said the whole
reason why no one in holography ever
even touched one of those diodes was the
fact that they said the coherence length
was a millimeter or less right and here
we're seeing it the last one that I had
set up on the uh the Optics table uh was
a bean path difference between the two
beams of 14 feet yeah I mean that's
incredible
he coherently determined by the number
of the modes they're operating
simultaneously
laser cavity you have those that are
related by 2L
laser normally has around five to ten
modes operate
operating
it's when you get out of phase between
waves from those modes that you need to
cohere and that happens in order I'll
have to explain two with a diode it
might
mode running it must be only one mode
operating
I can't really can't be any other
explanation and with one mode then then
your coherence length is going to be
understand essentially
as long as it's getting infected not by
it promotes them different modes
operating but followed by noise effects
difference in the short-term hitter
between between
them so I I would imagine you find one
mode one mode operating and I still
don't understand how you're getting
those bridges to just sit there
stationary if
now they are they're dead I mean
it's so disturbing to see it that you
just have to tap on the table to make
sure that this thing is still set up
right and if you're not seeing something
that's wrong because you know then they
just completely lock it's almost I don't
know have you seen The Fringe lockers
that have been used for uh the different
lasers where you set up a number of
different games
to create a fringe pattern and the photo
detector gets put into all that yeah
and yeah
only one Mode's operating and you're
controlling cavity length
to keep mode exactly where you want it
um
people destabilize bikini lasers
basically operate in such a way they're
set up with a header on inside the
cavity so that you only get one mode
operating and
sure at least maybe a piece of electric
as well feedback system
they can be
hundreds of people but a little bit I
mean that's just incredible
now the inner lines if you I I know that
and that line can be put on like one of
the old 125s are they very expensive to
purchase an italon to go on a laser I
imagine Yeah
by expensive I mean you're not talking
like a couple hundred dollars and you're
talking like a major investment yeah
although theoretically what is the just
the slab
in principle it's not anything that
fabulous but uh the ones you buy today
actually the frequency stabilize they
have
something honestly they're not even next
they're internal mirror too they're
inside the two there's some means
controlling the cavity length and
usually the middle wattage output
really low ones yeah
they have a set of lasers
and the electronics go with it for very
precise measurements the same thing the
thing you need to do if you are laying
down tracks on the hard drive these days
when you're preparing a hard drive you
need some way
somewhere in the order of wavelength of
light to get those tracks in the right
place
yeah well we can learn for hours yes
well we've got 11 hours and 22 minutes
of recording time left
filling up your hard drive yeah
send thanks a million I really enjoyed
talking with you and it was it was good
to be able to finally talk to you after
spending so much time over the past few
years you know on your site a lot of the
information that I got working with the
diodes that came off of your site in the
beginning just to try and get some sort
of an idea of what these things were
because you're so finicky oh
you know I mean you know you're popping
them like popcorn we tried a lot of
different things it's interesting some
people you know as I have in the fact
that some people say oh I hope the core
battery to the laser died and they were
just working great well we did that too
other people can look at them the wrong
way I've actually had one running off of
a battery
no photodiode feedback no driver nothing
good resistor and you know what the
current is at all temperatures it's safe
yeah that'll work fine but the problem
is that what the classic mistake is that
someone puts up a couple days adjust the
current so that you're the maximum turns
the power off goes gets a cup of coffee
he come back
it cools off oh I see turn the power on
the laser the optimal Power is coming up
50 blast the masses right off the time
yeah I popped into the point where the
little puff of white smoke that's
extreme that's normally the only way to
tell is to go in there with a microscope
where it says
this was in the early days of the
experimentation
well I can only get schematics and stuff
for your uh driver yeah I think Sam's
going to put um
link is just as good I don't get the
copies yeah that that website I've had
up since I think it might have been late
1994 when I put that up for holography
nothing like it is now I think I think
it was Netscape 1.0 is the browse on
there even that's the paper their Mosaic
I mean back to the early days you start
out with those days yeah yeah
yeah because I I know the only thing
that you could do with a web page was
either flush left or you could center
things and but there really wasn't
anything that you could do outside of
putting a picture up and uh yeah had a
graphical browser in some ways I wish I
kind of along for those old days I mean
people look at people don't even get me
started on some of these things yeah I
mean if you read if you read read the
cover page
[Music]
you know Graphics only if you want them
and you know waiting for 150k graphic to
download only to have it say welcome
that's right
yeah I mean it's the fun people they
probably say oh that's incredibly boring
but they stuff
you know I'm not going to get into that
but some of the manufacturers are the
worst I mean big manufacturers yeah
which is surprising some of the links
don't work and everything oh the links
don't work they're the worst if they
change their links they're the worst
they don't tell you where they you know
where they went and it definitely I I
guess I just don't have that business
mentality but the thing for me that you
know just take for example a laser
manufacturer
this is a bad site is to sell lasers to
technical
people yes it's not the management
that's buying lasers I mean it is really
the scientists engineers who are buying
lasers and they find this messenger do
not want the fluff
I think that's a fairly Universal I
think I can make that that's been fairly
safely
a vast majority of Science and Engineers
would want to just get at the
information yeah and yet there's so many
sites just incredibly have to wait wait
through their graphics and they're
they're flashing this
JavaScript the thin bomb and then once
it does come up and you see something
that's really interesting you click on
it and that page that under construction
and some of it some of these big
companies are like that yeah I mean they
have the dead links and they faint that
for a long time
I mean I won't name names but I could I
could like right now that that
important links are very dead yeah later
tonight I'll send you the links to those
uh I'm sorry 670 diodes and the prices
didn't you just fall over well it's like
this guy on eBay was selling today was
selling a uh I couldn't figure out what
it kind of diet it was laser diode
playing the original cost of 380 and
quantity 500 and uh it had to hide in
with 5
this guy that's been posting that he's
got uh the five milliwatt diodes from
now let me tell you about that guy and
you know like it's like hello there's
some information here yeah let me tell
you about that guy I sent an email like
that I sent email said look what kind of
diets are these are they uh you know you
haven't been answering emails like what
are these are they are they modules are
they diets or what's the actual part
number
decide anywhere
he wrote back to me so sorry about that
um you know I'll send you a sample if
you send yourself a dress down below I'm
still waiting
and he does that every story yeah
I don't understand like some people I I
don't know he's really dropped the
prices
12 15 10 bucks or something
what their mentality is when they post
some of these things and expect there'll
be a stampede if
orders so right after I announced that
uh little
diode system that we put together
someone had posted something saying has
anyone heard anything about the laser
system that Frank de Freitas and Sam
Savage made it looks really good or
something I hope it's ready for
Christmas 99. right you know I mean I
almost fell out of my chair I said now
doesn't that look like me posting other
under another screen name trying to get
a but I had no idea who that was I
honestly don't so I had a poster
response to it you know the way I was
feeling that weekend all I wanted to do
was sleep until Christmas I wasn't
worried about one of the lasers
what are you planning to do with are you
are you going to offer the hit or yeah I
just printed out all the stuff from cdrh
today that's why I was so curious about
how some of these places sell these
lasers because requirements you know for
the class 3B is a shutter you know right
right
a key on off switch with a delay and uh
have anything any of my uh
slazers that I've purchased yeah I I
have a feeling
the trade and lasers is just kind of
under the rug yeah under the table I
think we want to do it by the book and
you know yeah and maybe make a little
small business out of it you know for
the two of us sure you put in a little
box with a key switch and go through the
cbrh but I guess you have to go through
the cprh procedure
yeah there's a 35 page application you
have to fill out right right but I'll
tell you I think they need to rewrite
some of that stuff yes it's for guests
mostly for gas lasers you know like once
you open up the housing how much
radiation is the person exposed to well
that doesn't even apply you know to the
little diet that does apply
dtfs lasers IR flux living around it's I
mean you're right they probably have to
rewrite it but I I don't think it's
totally yeah
I didn't think about those when you
lose when you've got the infrared
radiation
if your topical helping capture
everything there's going to be some some
of the visible popping around bouncing
back and forth but if you know if you
put that thing I guess what you put in a
little little case which
a little indicator like which
photographers do not like because who
wants the light on when you've got light
sensitive plates in the room what what
are the ethical colors they uh usually
usually a deep green which the red sense
of the plate you know doesn't have a lot
of sensitivity to in the first place but
I I would always take black
but maybe I shouldn't say that I always
used to take black masking tape and
cover up put up the lights anyway but I
don't want any lights go anywhere in the
lab sure we're seeing about you know
we'll never know but we're not rich now
in fact I ordered some parts today and I
had to go online to see how much money I
had in the account so that it wouldn't
bounce when you know they they took it
out of the account that's the question I
have for you is how do you install
everything I do is out of pocket I have
no funding whatsoever I'm just a guy in
this here in downtown that does the
holography you know and there are no
backers or investment bankers or
anything like that
right
things start out I believe the Newport
from what I understand that was to you
guys that put their whole first catalog
together and it's sitting with one of
the guys wives at the dining room table
probably through the typewriter there's
an interesting book I may have read on
the history of lasers it goes from
before 1960 until uh maybe only 1970
that's the network built worth reading
it talks about you know died like that
exactly where two guys got together I
don't know Spectrum physics is one of
the examples in the early days they were
just like kind of building lasers lasers
in their basements
and to to uh universities and Industry
because I think it was just such an
inflation for lasers before the laser
companies really got rolling yeah I
think some of those same lasers appear
on eBay
yeah
eBay eBay I
have bookmark
my search strings to eBay and I keep
track of it that's kind of interesting
watching
watching bids and some of the amounts
that people are willing to spend
and then you see the same thing pop up
on eBay a couple weeks later and it
doesn't get many you know because the
guy got it inside well the one person
would buy bought it there that cleaned
it up stared at for a while and said
well okay I've seen that now I can sell
them okay and then the next time he
never doesn't get a fraction away
my first hologram it was probably in
1964 so I think it was Scientific
American okay published a hologram in
the centerfold that's when I took that
thing into my high school and they had
this fabulous helium neon laser it's
probably one of these pieces of junk and
the scientific or Metro places but it
was a helium yellow light it was a real
laser yeah and I got a like a lens on a
on a van a chemistry of for holding
that's too much only stuck a lens to
expand the beam and wow
great yeah oh yeah
but they were recommending you need to
start with a pinhole or whatever and you
know I recently had a chance to see an
ad for a one milliwatt helium neon laser
from back in 60s and it might have been
back in 64 or so and I think it was
and that was in 64. yeah that's like 57
000 yeah I mean I don't think I don't
think a lot of cars were three thousand
nine hundred dollars
1962 we spayed we paid 7 1900 for a
Chevy Bel Air there you go it was it was
twice the price of a Bel Air for a one
milliwatt helium neon laser I wish I
could find that out I don't know if I
have the ad here I put that up on my
website
what can I do with that ad where did I
see it it's going to drive me nuts now
I've got to find it it was just
incredible I've got to find it
all right I'm going to run I gotta pick
my daughter up actually so good night
all right talk to you later and good
night from Hollow talk we're going to
cut it right out here good night see you
later